AJA WASHINGTON

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

in linkedin.com/in/ajawashington

github.com/ajawashington aja.washington13@gmail.com

615-732-9825



OBJECTIVE

I have built my career tackling many different roles in a variety of industries as an instructor, assistant, and leader to companies. Simultaneously working with a brilliant team by my side, and handling projects independently.

My life's work is committed to instilling divergent thinking to the global community; enhancing our humanity and humility. This shift in perspective begins with solving problems in a dynamic way and is what caught my interest in software development. Technology is the leading force of our society, its powerful, accessible features grants anyone the power to influence ideas, structures, and policy at a rapid rate.

With my experience in arts & entertainment, hospitality, human instruction and study, I plan to allow my skill in software to build something focused on redefining the global idea of living and creating; influencing fruitful, invigorating lifestyles.

My dedication to growth is what drives me to change my life and the world around me.

PROJECTS

FRONT END CAPSTONE

beyGood

beyGood is a open, public charity application. Individuals make charity requests to assist with daily financial setbacks. This application was inspired by American singer, Beyoncé Knowles's charity initiative, BEYGOOD Foundation, who works with local charities to help fund raise and raise awareness for local causes.

This app allows donors to provide the funds, services, or items to a partnering business or organization. The charity individual will receive a credited account with said business or organization and be able to redeem requests.

- Full CRUD functionality using React
- Utilizing API fetch calls to a local JSON database
- CSS used for styling and user experience

FRONT END https://github.com/ajawashington/BeyGoodReact

This application was later refactored to be full stack MVC application.

BACK END https://github.com/ajawashington/BeyGoodAPI

BACK END CAPSTONE

EDUCATION

Nashville School of the Arts High School Diploma Dance Major

Nashville Software School cohort 37

TECH STACK

















EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Full Stack Developer

Nashville Software School | Nov 2019 - May 2020

Six month intensive software boot camp program learning full stack technologies. Building multiple local applications individually and in a group setting. Consistent, challenging work environment with junior and senior developers

- Version control utilizing Git and GitHub
- Using ERDs, wireframes, user stories to determine functionality and dependencies Built CRUD applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React
- Queried databases using SQL to build server side applications in C#
- Building full stack applications communicating with an API database

HOSPITALITY

North Italia | Nashville, TN | Nov 2019 - Present Iberian Pig | Decatur, GA | Mar 2018 - Aug 2018 Barcelona Wine Bar | Nashville, TN | Jan 2017 - Sep 2017

Bartender

Monday Night Brewing | Dec 2017 - Mar 2018

- Providing guests with a personalized, attentive, and informative dining experience
- Full knowledge of all beverages, wine, food, company history and culture
- Delivery and supervision of adult alcohol consumption
- Catering to the needs of all guests and assisting team members

Team Lead

The Urban Juicer | Nashville, TN | Dec 2018 - May 2019

- Responsible for documenting daily inventory, food temps, and sales
- Opening and closing duties for food and beverage; key holder
- On-duty of supervising transactions and sales
- Leading staff during high volume, demanding service

Tarallucci e vino | New York, NY | Jan 2014 - May 2016

- Manage the flow of seating, service, and all bookings
- Assisting with private events and large parties
- Daily administrative tasks for owner and managers

ARTS & ENTERTAINMENT

Dance Instructor

Platinum Dance Studio | Lebanon, TN | 2018 World Class Performance Center | Bethpage, NY | 2015 -2017 Metuchen Dance Center | Metuchen, NJ | 2015 - 2017 Williamsburg Arts & Movement Center | Brooklyn, NY | Sept 2014 - Feb 2015 Nashville School of the Arts | Nashville, TN | 2013 - 2016

- Led movement classes of many different genres for ages 5 adult
- Choreographed and rehearsed recital & competition performances
- Teaching curriculum was focused on movement history, vocabulary, and events
- After-School pick up and homework assistance

Touring Staff

VIP DANCE | New Orleans, LA | Jan 2015 - Jun 2015

- Sales Associate for merchandise
- Tracker of scores and awards
- · Backstage manager and assistant to host

Spring Production Assistant

Calm & Sense Creations | New York, NY | Mar 2015 - Aug 2015

- Rehearsal, meeting, and appointment scheduling
- Production based research
- Create video promotion for performances
- Organize contracts digitally and physically